<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | KRAS Comutation</title>
    <link>https://project-notebook-comutation.netlify.com/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://project-notebook-comutation.netlify.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 06:58:30 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://project-notebook-comutation.netlify.com/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://project-notebook-comutation.netlify.com/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>KRAS Allele-Specific Synthetic Lethality</title>
      <link>https://project-notebook-comutation.netlify.com/project/allele-specific-synthetic-lethality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 06:58:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://project-notebook-comutation.netlify.com/project/allele-specific-synthetic-lethality/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;synthetic-lethality&#34;&gt;Synthetic Lethality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Synthetic lethality refers to a genetic interaction whereby one mutation sensitizes an organism to another normally-benign mutation.
This overlaps with &amp;ldquo;dependency&amp;rdquo; whereby the first mutation pushes the organism into a state of reliance on specific functions.
Blocking (by mutation or inhibition) this function would cause the mutant organism to die, but not effect the wild-type organisms.
Thus, a current goal of much of cancer research is focussed on finding synthetic lethal interactions with common oncogenes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;allele-specific-synthetic-lethality&#34;&gt;Allele-specific synthetic lethality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this portion of the Comutation project is to identify synthetic lethal interactions with specific &lt;em&gt;KRAS&lt;/em&gt; alleles.
From a theory point-of-view, these interactions would provide information on the differences between the alleles.
From a therapeutics point-of-view, the identification of allele-specific interactions could be used to further personalize treatment strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data&#34;&gt;Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this analysis, we used the Cancer Dependency Mapping (DepMap) data.
In this ongoing study, the cell lines from the Cancer Cell Line Encyclopedia (CCLE) were analyzed in a genome-wide, CRISPR-Cas9, loss-of-function screen whereby each gene was systemically knocked-out and the loss of growth of the cell line was measured.
Thankfully, many omics data are available for the cell lines, including RNA expression, mutations, and CNA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RC-Test for Comutation</title>
      <link>https://project-notebook-comutation.netlify.com/project/rc-test-for-comutation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 06:58:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://project-notebook-comutation.netlify.com/project/rc-test-for-comutation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
